

Kenneth Ly

Computer Science Student

7704 Anthony Ln Plano, Texas, 75024 kenneth.ly19@gmail.com 5054172653

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kenneth-ly-b73158

Portfolio: https://kll505.github.io/

Computer Science student enrolled at the University of Texas at Dallas with a 3.9 GPA and Dean's List accreditation, focused on building experiences and relationships to help guide me into my professional career. I have been programming for 5 years and am experienced in C++, C, C#, Java, and Python, and have worked with ASP.net core and VUE.js frameworks but I'm always eager to learn new skills. Currently employed as a web application developer at Ayoka Systems and am always looking for new opportunities to advance my career.

Key Skills

- Java
- C/C++
- 5 1
- Python
- JavascriptHTML/CSS
- ASP.Net Core
- Vue.js
- TypeScript
- Data Structures and Algorithims
- Unit Testing
- Relational Databases
- Music Production

Professional Experience

Web Application Developer

Ayoka Software | May 2022 - Present

- Worked with a small team in the development of web applications using frameworks such as ASP.Net core and VUE.js
- Worked heavily with C#, HTML, CSS3, JavaScript, and Typescript languages for programming.
- Interacted with a SQL relational database, performing queries and uploads to manage data for the application
- Utilized Javascript libraries and frameworks including AG Grid, and jQuery, and used AJAX and JSON
 coding to maintain the front-end of the application
- Designed code that strictly followed MVT architecture to address separations of concern and the flow of the application
- Troubleshoot and debugged code ensuring compatibility with devices, browsers, and operating systems.
- · Adapted quickly to a constantly changing, deadline-driven environment
- Used AWS S3 to store files uploaded to the application in the cloud
- Used Git to maintain the organization of our team's code and manage versions of the application

Teaching Assistant

University of Texas at Dallas | August 2022 - December 2022

- Assisted in the course "ECS1100 Introduction to Engineering and Computer Science"
- Helped professor with classroom management and document coordination to maintain a positive learning environment.
- Met with students outside of class to answer questions, explain difficult concepts, and address individual concerns.
- Delivered clear, effective feedback to improve the quality and efficiency of student-written computer programs.
- Recorded grades for coursework and tests in an online reporting system.

Pharmacy Technician

CVS Health, Plano, Texas, United States | September 2021 - September 2022

- Collected co-payments or full payments from customers.
- · Answered incoming phone calls and addressed questions from customers and healthcare providers.
- Assisted pharmacist by filling prescriptions for customers and responding to patient questions regarding prescription and medication-specific issues.
- Worked with computerized and automated systems for dispensing medications and editing new patient profiles.

Education

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

The University of Texas at Dallas August 2021 - Present

- Part of the Deans List which is the top 10% of all undergraduate students
- 3.9 GPA with 76 credit hours
- Expected to graduate in the spring of 2024

Projects

Polygon Area Calculator

This program can calculate the area of any polygon given the coordinate points of each vertex using a dynamic 3d array and store all of these areas within a linked list that can be sorted or searched through. The purpose of this program is to compare different delivery drivers by using the calculated area from the polygons created by their delivery routes.

Route Tracker

A program that can take in a file that contains a series of locations and their routes to other destinations and implement this data into a weighted graph represented by an adjacency matrix. This program can then take in another file that contains a list of drivers and their routes along with these locations. The program can use this graph to determine if the driver's route is valid and the total distance the driver will travel and print this information to the console.

Basic Linux Shell

A program that functions as a basic shell that can be run in Linux. It uses execvp to execute commands inputted by the user. It has access to basic system commands as well as the ability to run executables. A built-in history command is provided that allows the user to view the history of the commands entered into the shell and execute

them. This shell also supports inter-process communication through the use of pipes and can be used to execute pipe commands.

Simple Network Database

A program built in Linux using sockets and client-server architecture to emulate a remote network database. The program allows clients to connect to a server by giving a DNS and port number. Once connected, clients can then store, access, and delete records (which is a 512-byte string that consists of a name and 10-digit ID) within this server's database stored in a local file on the server's machine. Multiple clients can connect to the server at once and perform actions synchronously due to the implementation of multithreading and locks.